- You 've sold us a bill of goods , Gordon .
You promised us new drugs to fight everything
from the common cold to cancer .
- And we 'll deliver everything that we promised .
- I 'm sorry , Gordon , but the adventure is over .
We re exercising our option to liquidate
Byron Mitchell Research Limited .
- Jack , show these people how filthy rich
we 're gonna make them , please .
- Cordon , I don 't think you understand what I just said .
- Oh , I think I understand .
Jack .
- Perrinia immortalis , the Blood Orchid .
First described in 1392 by Houghton ,
the last person to see it
until our exploratory team brought a Sample from Borneo .
The Blood Orchid lies dormant for seven years ,
then blooms for just six months .
- Which means we just got lucky as hell , gentlemen .
- I don 't suppose anyone here
is familiar with the Hayflick limit ?
- Hayflick proposed that a cell
could only replicate 56 times
before it died from a buildup of toxins .
According to him , it 's the reason that we die .
- But what if we could transcend that limit ?
- That would be impossible .
- Not according to our data .
Our research indicates the presence of a chemical
in Perrinia immortalis
that can significantly prolong cellular life .
- I can 't support this .
- Does that mean what I think it moans ?
- Are we talking about a pharmaceutical equivalent
to the fountain of youth ?
- Exactly .
- That 'd be bigger than Viagra .
- Have you put this into human trials ?
- We can 't yet .
Our sample was degraded in the initial Study .
We need more of the orchid .
- See , and that 's our only problem , gentlemen .
That orchid is only in bloom tor another two weeks .
- Well , what the hell are you waiting for ?
Oct your asses down to Borneo .
- Yes .
- Welcome to Borneo . - Thanks .
- What 's wrong with this picture ?
- I don 't know , let me see , you 're in it ?
- We don 't have a boat , okay ?
Your company had one responsibility , to get a boat ,
and you 've already managed to screw it up .
- Wait , wait , wait a minute .
Your girl chartered the boat , not us .
- No , no , Sam confirmed with the company last night .
They 're still waiting for your payment .
- Hey , hey , I 've got something .
Payment cleared .
- Really ?
- Where 's the boat ?
- It 's not coming .
All of the charter companies have shut down .
No one 'll risk going upriver until after the rainy season .
- And when 's that ?
- Two , three weeks .
- The orchid 's only in bloom for one more week , tops .
- There 's a local captain named Jin-Soon .
I 'm told he 'll take anyone upriver for the right price .
- are you sure this is the place ?
- They said the one with the red door .
- I bet you any kind of money
there 's somebody 's playing Russian roulette in there .
- Well , maybe we 'll get lucky and they 'll give you a turn .
- Hey , why don 't you two just get a room .
Come on , Sam .
Wait here .
- Yeah , if you insist .
- Hey , hey .
Jin-Soon .
Jin-Soon ?
- Your Indonesian sucks .
Stick to English .
- We heard you could take us upriver .
- In rainy season ?
Won 't be cheap .
- We can pay you 25,000 .
- I 'll have a talk with the captain .
- What do you mean , you 're not the captain ?
- Jin-Soon !
These tourists need a boat .
I told them not in the rainy season .
- You 're Jin-Soon ?
- Local nickname .
Name 's Johnson , Bill Johnson .
It 's a pronunciation thing .
And you can rent my boat for 25 grand .
Now , you want me to drive it ,
well , that 'll cost you 50 .
- 50 grand , are you high ?
You know what , please don 't answer that question .
There is no way I 'm trusting thiS guy with the expedition .
- Listen , lady .
Let 's cut the bullshit , please .
If one of the other charter companies could take you ,
you 'd be on the river by now .
You only came to me because you 're desperate .
50 grand 's my price .
Take it or leave it .
- I 've seen subway cars in better Shape than thiS .
- Yeah , she may be ugly , but she puts out .
- Ah , shit !
- What took you so long ?
- Hey , you try getting a GPS locator , a Sat-Nav EchoStar
and a UV spectrometer past Indonesian customs .
- Complaining already . - Yeah .
- Would you rather be back in the office ?
- Hell , yeah .
Girl , I had courtside seats at the Garden Saturday night .
I was gonna sit right between Spike and Woody .
Oh , man , is that our ride ?
- Look at the bright side , Cole .
At least the weather 's nice .
- Ben Douglas , team doctor .
You must be Sam .
- Yeah , we spoke on the phone .
Glad to have you aboard .
- I 'm gonna get you for this .
- Oh , yeah , this could be fun .
- You can forget about that , dog .
That 's one car you ain 't never gonna catch .
- There 's always a way .
- Your team 's a little green , huh ?
- My former grad students .
Best in their field .
Here 's a tip for Wexell-Hall :
you want the best young talent , recruit early .
- Yes , I 'm sure Sam 's very talented .
- I think I resent that .
- You and the other gal can stay in here .
- You live here .
- The way you say that , I can tell you 're impressed .
All right , and if you need anything .
Well , if you need anything , you 're shit out of luck .
- Okay .
Now , this is where the exploratory team found the orchid .
In the Selatan Basin .
It took them three days to get upriver .
- Yeah , that was before the rainy season .
Some of these waterways could be dangerous now .
- You said you could got us there safely .
- And I will .
But safe isn 't always quick .
We 'll work our way upriver one bend at a time .
If I don 't like what I see , we change course .
You can 't chart the fastest route before you begin .
- Already have .
Check , aight .
Now , we 're uplinked in real time to NASA and AsiaSatCom .
Now , under ideal conditions ,
This is the fastest route .
But once we superimpose weather patterns
for the past 10 years and then extrapolate ,
bingo , it 's Padrang to the Selatan Basin .
I 'm a bad man .
- All right , look , we got less than a week
to get to that orchid .
Now , if you can 't get the job done ,
give us our money back and we 'll get somebody who can .
- I 'll get you there .
- Ugh .
God help me .
Ugh .
Something attacked me , something attacked me !
Oh , my god !
- Man , she said something attacked her .
- No , no , no , no , no !
- It 's okay , it 's okay .
What the hell did you do ?
You scared him .
- I scared him ?
- This is Kong .
Kong lives here .
You 're guests .
Be nice .
- Disgusting animal .
- Uh , you okay now ?
- I 'm fine , just keep your hands off of me .
- Oh , yeah , well , it 's gonna be tough , but I 'll try .
No , no , the S-1 has to be on file before the week is out .
- Yeah , yeah . - No , I don 't care .
See , that 's the point . - Yeah , yeah , hello ?
- No , the S-1 needs to be on file before the week is out .
- Yes , we were able to get on the river ...
- Well , that 's the whole purpose .
We need the comments back from the SEC .
- Uh-huh , yeah . - Excuse me , excuse me .
I 'm trying ... - lt 's the only place
I got reception . - No , juSt get it done , okay ?
- No , that 's impossible . - We need to be ready to go ,
effectively ... - Three , four days ...
Hello ? - Hello ?
- Hello ! - Bob !
- Damn ! - Damn it !
- Try my phone .
Works just as good , but it 's free .
- Oh , okay , okay , maybe you can use my Special antenna
to boost your reception .
- We 're dealing with a lithophytic vine ,
so we want to search any rock face .
- Now , this ridge here seems a good bot .
- Sam .
Come on , Sam , what do you say ?
We 're young , we 're Single , we 're in Borneo .
What do you got to lose ?
You 're not satisfied , you walk away , no commitments .
- No commitments ?
That 's your pitch ?
- Did I say no commitments ?
I meant marry me .
- Am I gonna be dealing with thiS for the next two weeks ?
- Yep .
- So you were one of Jack 's students ?
- Yeah , he was teaching a seminar on botanical pharmacology .
Soon as I finished my dissertation , he hired me .
- Well , that 's one way to get a leg up .
- What 's that supposed to mean ?
- I had a professor who wanted to hire me
right out of school .
Of course , he wanted me to be his secretary .
- Look , it I 've done something to offend you in any way ...
- No , no , dear , not at all .
Actually , I admire you .
Took me 10 years to get where I am .
Clearly , your generation has it figured out .
- Man , this is good , man .
Where 'd you learn to cook like this ?
- It 's just a little recipe I picked up in Sri Lanka .
- What were you doing there ?
- Doctors Without Borders .
It 's my day job .
- You guys expect to need a doctor for Some reason ?
- Can 't get the expedition bonded without one .
- Well , you just think of me as a charming insurance policy .
- Hey !
You 've had your dinner .
Oct out of here .
Ah , what 'd I say ?
- There 's not that much ...
- I 'm serious , Gail , I 'm not sleeping up there .
I ain 't sleeping on the floor .
I ain 't sleeping on no damn .
- Oh , shit , what was that ?
- What the hell was that ?
- Something 's getting eaten .
- By what ?
- Everything gets eaten out here .
It 's the jungle .
Kong .
Hey , you guys seen Kong ?
- No , not since last night .
Come on , man . - Why 's that ?
Where are you ?
Kong ?
- We need those results by next month
if we want the FDA off our backs .
Hello ?
Shit !
I can 't hoar you !
Can you hear me now ?
How about now ?
- We can .
- Can you hear me now ?
- Oh , shit . - Gail , oh , my god .
Oh , my god , shit .
- Stop the boat !
- I 'll go .
- All right . - Hey , Gail !
Can you hear me now ?
- Oh , I 'm gonna kill you .
- Stroke , Gail , stroke , come on .
- Watch your back . - Come on , Stroke .
- Hey , Gail , how 's the water ?
- Maybe you should drop the phone .
It 's probably holding you back .
- All right . - Stay calm , Gail .
- Come on - Come on , stay calm .
- Use your phone as a flotation device .
- All right , come on , Gail .
You 're almost there , Gail . - Come on ,
it 's just like a phone .
- I got it .
- Oh !
- Holy shit ! - Holy shit .
- Get out ! - Hurry up !
- Hurry up , hurry up !
- Come on , come on ! - Grab it .
- Look out !
- Mitchell . - Oh , my god .
- Yeah , Bill !
Oct him , Bill !
Oct him in the eye , Bill !
- Bill ?
- Where 'd he go ?
- Where 'd he go ? - Bill , Bill !
- I don 't see him .
Where 's he gone ? - Oh , my god .
- Oh , shit , you won .
- You 're okay ?
- I lost my phone .
- Sorry to hoar it .
- That was either the bravest
or the stupidest thing I 've ever seen .
- It 's a fine line .
- Good as new . - Thanks .
- To Gail , who knows it 's better to cat than be eaten .
- To Gail . - Hear , hear , baby .
- Almost eaten just to find a flower .
Hardly seems worth it . - Oh , it 's worth it .
I mean , think about it , right ?
A pill that you take every day for the rest of your lite .
Now , even if we charge , say , a dollar a pop ,
we 're billionaires .
- Yeah , that 's what I 'm talking about , baby .
- At $ 100 a bottle ,
I 'll dive in that river and fight that croc myself .
- So how many flowers does it take to save the world ?
- We figure 50 orchids
will yield about an ounce of chemical .
- You could have a football field full of those orchids ,
still doesn 't mean you can get it through human trials .
- She doesn 't even believe in you .
- Comes with the territory .
In research , you 've got to go out on a limb .
And there 's always someone waiting to chop it off .
- Where the hell have you been , huh ?
- Damn that thing !
- Where you been , boy ?
Calm down , calm down .
- Poor guy . - Lt 's okay , it 's all right .
- Looks like ho 's seen a ghost .
- It 's all right .
It 's all right .
- What if Gail 's right ?
I mean , colls in a Petri dish are one thing .
Human trials are another .
- She 's wrong .
And when Perrinia immortalis goes to product ,
and you and I can cash in our Stock options ,
we 'll rub her face in it .
- Stock options ?
- I spoke to Mitchell .
We 're each giving you half a point .
- I don 't know what to say .
- Don 't say anything .
You deserve it .
All this wouldn 't be possible without your work .
- Jack .
I thought we decided against that .
- Yeah , yeah , you 're right .
It would be fun , though .
I mean , here we are , travelling upriver
to the greatest discovery of our careers , and ,
now , if this orchid thing works out , then , who knows ?
- Is that why I 'm here ?
So you can give us one more try ?
- You 're here because you 're the best researcher I 've got .
- Am I interrupting something ?
- No , no , I was , um ,
I was just going to bed . - Yeah .
Well , before you do that , we need to talk .
We got a problem .
See the water level ? - Uh-huh .
- In high water , the Mendranang gets rough .
Now , what we could do is turn around
and try to find another course .
But that would take at least two days .
- We don 't have the time .
- If the river becomes impassable ,
it 's gonna take a lot longer .
- And if we turn back , then we 're definitely screwed .
We 're gonna have to risk it .
- What if I don 't wanna risk it ?
- Do you have any idea what this flower means ?
We 're talking about
the biggest medical discovery in history .
- Wow , that does sound great , Jack .
But I was never any good at history .
You want me to risk the Mendranang ,
it 's gonna cost you an extra 50,000 .
- Done .
- Done ?
Don 't you gotta ask the boss lady or Something ?
- I 'll pay it myself .
- All right , you got yourself a deal .
But if we hit trouble ,
your people do what I say , you got that ?
- You 're the captain .
- Research proposals ?
- Yeah , research proposals .
You 're not the only company we 're in bed with .
- Yeah , but we 're the prettiest and most popular .
It 's like sleeping with the head cheerleader .
- Not quite .
- Come on , you know you love us .
- I love your cash .
- Then why don 't you let me get a look at that file .
I mean , after this orchid thing goes bust ,
you 're gonna be finished at Wexell-Hall
unless you got something else lined up .
- You really wanna see us fail , don 't you ?
- No , I just think that you will .
I am a scientist , you know .
- Scientist ?
What are you doing at Wexell-Hall ?
- I like science .
I just like money better .
- I 'll drink to that .
- River 's flooded .
We can 't see the banks .
- Miss our turnoff ?
- It 's just ahead .
- What the hell was that ?
- Rudder 's jammed . - What ?
Watch out .
Shit !
Oct up .
Everybody up .
- Hey .
- What 's going on ?
- goddammit .
Oh , shit , we 've blown the head gasket .
- We all right ?
- Hey , what 's going on ?
- What is it ? - We got problems .
- Hey , what 's wrong , man ? - Bill , wait .
What are you talking about ?
- We 're shot . - What problems ?
- Son of a bitch .
the current 's too strong .
- We missed our turnoff . - I know .
Come on , baby .
- Come on , man .
- What is it ?
- What do you see ?
- Come on .
You got this .
Come on , girl .
- Everybody , hang on !
- Hang on to what ?
Come on !
Oh , shit !
- Holy shit .
- Oh , god .
- It 's sinking , it 's sinking !
- Where 's Cole ?
- Swim to the rocks , this way .
- Keep going .
Come on , get to the rocks .
Where 's Cole ?
Cole ! - Where 's Cole ?
- Over there !
Over there , over there !
- Come on , man .
Give me your hand !
- Come on .
You got it , Sam , come on .
- Come on , Sam , give me your hand .
I 've got you , I 've got you , whoa .
Give me your hand , give me your hand .
- Okay , I got her .
- You almost got us killed !
- You think I wanted this ?
I just lost my damn boat !
- You 're gonna lose your damn payday
if you don 't got us out of this .
- You said you could got us there safely .
If you knew it was that dangerous ,
you should 've turned around .
- That 's enough !
There 's nothing we can do about that now .
It 's a waste of energy .
What have we got ?
- Some Specimen jars , a map , a little water , no food .
- Hard drive 's ruined .
- Well , pretty much all the equipment 's Shot .
Except one of the sat phones still works .
It 's online .
- Thank god , we can call the police .
- Police .
the nearest river patrol is back in Padrang .
The only way to get to us is over that .
- are you saying wc 're stuck here ?
- Maybe not .
We 're here .
The valley 's completely flooded .
But I got a friend who operates a boat on the Tokut River .
I can give him a call , and ho can meet us here at Naga Rock .
- How far is that ?
- I don 't know .
A two-day hike down the river .
But if we bushwhack , we cut at least a day off the trek .
- Oh , my god , you wanna go through that ?
- It 's the shortest way .
We could be safely in the Tokut by nightfall .
- So we can continue with the expedition .
- Yeah , I 'll got you to the flower .
- I don 't care about that flower , just get us to Safety .
- It 's the same thing .
Now , we can either be on my buddy 's boat in 10 hours
or we can sit here and wait for the river patrol for days .
- Your friend , is he reliable ?
- Absolutely .
You 'd better not screw me on this .
- Sounds like you 're already screwed , mate .
- Pay you two grand .
I need you on this one , John .
- Yes , yes , so it seems .
Look , Billy , I 'd love to help you out ,
but I 'm flat out , mate , you know .
Probably squeeze you in for , Say , five grand ?
- You 're killing me .
- That 's mates ' rates .
Or you could always hike back to Padrang ,
if you wanna save bucks .
Up to you , pal .
- Fine , five . - Yeah !
- But you 'd better be there .
Otherwise , I 'll tell your wife
about that little side trip to Bangkok .
- Wife 's long gone , Billy .
Long gone , mate .
- All right , people , we 're on .
Saddle up .
Stay together .
This jungle is all green all the time ,
and you will got lost .
- It 's like doing a StairMaster in a sauna .
- Yeah , I might die of a heat stroke ,
but I 'll have a nice tight ass .
- That 's the spirit , Cole .
- You want me to grab that ?
- Is that a trick question ?
Here , man .
- Right between Spike and Woody .
Right between Spike and Woody .
- You okay , Sam ?
- I 'm fine .
- See , a crisis separates the real men from the pretenders .
- Yeah , can see that .
- What , that ?
That 's nothing .
- I tricked him into taking my bag .
- Hey , mind if I give it a try ?
- Knock yourself out .
- Hey .
I 'm sorry about your boat .
- Yeah , well .
It was a piece of shit anyway .
- Can we go around ?
- Yeah , we could , but we 'd lose another day .
let 's go .
- Shit .
- Hey , knock it off .
- Shit !
What was that ?
- What was what ?
- Something just moved . - Oh , please , don 't say that .
- No , I 'm serious , something just moved past me .
- Something juSt moved as in something 's alive ?
- Yeah , man , shit , shit !
Yo , there it is again , man , there 's something in here .
- Cole , there 's probably a million things in here .
- He 's right .
Just keep moving .
- Stop it .
I swear to god , if you don 't stop it .
Very funny .
Ben ?
- Ben ? - Ben ?
- Where 'd he go ? - Shit .
Ben !
Ben ?
- Ben !
- Help me !
- Ben ! - Ben !
- Run ! - Run !
- What the hell was that thing ?
- Anaconda . - Oh , great .
- There 's snakes out here that big ?
- Yes , but there 's no ... - But what ?
That thing swallowed him whole !
- if you calm down and listen
for a second - No , no , no , no !
- I can explain to you ... - No , you calm down
and you listen !
Ben was eaten by a freaking snake , okay ?
A freaking snake !
- Cole . - Oh , god !
Oh , god .
Oh , my god , I mean ... - Cole .
- Oh , my god , did you see that thing ?
We don 't got a chance against Something like that !
Mitchell , Mitchell , listen to me , man .
I watch the Discovery Channel , okay ?
I 'm telling you , we got no chance , we got no chance !
We 're like mice in an aquarium , do you understand ?
I mean , we 're gonna die , girl .
We 're gonna die , we 're gonna die !
- Cole , Cole .
Calm down , okay ?
Okay ? - Okay , Jack , I 'm okay .
- Okay . - I 'm okay .
- Okay . - I 'll juSt .
I 'm , I 'm , I 'm gonna sit right here .
I 'm sorry .
- Listen , anacondas are territorial .
A snake that size will hunt a huge area .
There won 't be another one for miles .
We gotta got to the boat .
It 's not that far .
So if we keep moving and stick together , we should be fine .
- We should be ?
- How big do they get ?
- That was the biggest one I 've ever Seen by far .
A freak of nature .
The odds of running into another one that size
are astronomical .
- Yeah , but how do we know
that the one that got Ben is not gonna come after us ?
- It takes them weeks to digest .
Meal like that , he 'll be Sleeping it off for a while .
- Let 's just get to that boat and get home .
- What about the orchid ?
- You 've gotta be kidding me .
- It won 't be in bloom for another seven years .
- This expedition is over , Jack .
- Now , hold on a second , Gail .
There 's a lot of money at stake here , okay ?
- I don 't care !
Ben is dead !
We have lost someone .
As Wexell-Hall 's representative ,
I am calling this expedition off .
- You don 't have the authority .
- Check your contract . - In case you hadn 't noticed ,
we 're in the middle of the jungle .
At this point , your authority is what we say it is .
- Jack , I 'm with her .
I gotta get the hell out of here , man .
- Look , Ben was my friend , okay ?
I got him into this ,
and no one fees worse about it than I do .
I don 't wanna do anything stupid .
I just wanna accomplish what we came here tor .
If we turn back now , Ben 's death would be for nothing .
- Let 's just get back to the boat .
We can regroup and make our decision then .
- Fine .
- Jack , maybe Gail 's right .
- She 's just scared .
Once we got back to the boat , she 'll be okay .
- When we get back to the boat , thiS expedition is over .
the only place I 'm taking these people is to Safety .
- Hey , hey , hey , we had a deal .
- Keep your money , doc .
Someone is dead .
We 're officially in over our heads .
- You just said we wouldn 't run into another one
of those things .
- And we probably won 't , but I can 't guarantee it .
So I 'll get you to the boat , and after that , we 're done .
- Well , that answers it . - That answers nothing .
I 'll just throw more money at him
when we get back to the boat .
If he doesn 't take it , I 'll offer his friend the same deal .
- Jack , maybe we should listen ...
- Sam , if we don 't get to that orchid now ,
all of our work will have been for nothing .
I need your support , okay ?
You have as much riding on this as I do .
Don 't let me down .
- I saw this special on Animal planet .
Anacondas are vicious , man .
I mean , they hunt for sport .
They don 't even need to See you to cat you .
I mean , they just use their flicking tongues
to sense your body heat ... - Will you shut the hell up ?
- And I knew this guy who knew thiS other guy
who used to shoot documentaries ,
and he won 't down to the Amazon with thiS crew once ,
and they were all eaten by snakes .
That 's a true story .
- Come on , you knew a guy who knew a guy ,
that 's an urban myth .
- I 'm sorry about Ben .
I never should 've stayed on the Mendranang .
- What do you mean ?
- Well , I figured he didn 't tell the others ,
but I thought you know .
- Knew what ?
- Byron offered me an extra 50 grand to stay on the river .
I told him it might get rough , but he wanted to risk it .
Hey , don 't blame him .
It was my call .
I took the money .
I thought I could get us through .
You wanna blame anyone ?
You blame me .
- These boots are killing me .
Colo .
- What ?
- You got some .
- Oh , god , what is that ?
Oct it off , get it off , got it off !
Oh , my god , take it off ! - All right , relax .
- Help me , help me ! - All right , hold on , hold on .
- Help me , help me !
Get it off , get it off ! - Hold on , hey .
Okay , calm down .
Calm down .
Colo !
Cole , calm down .
- What is it , what is it ?
Oct it off , Bill .
Oct it off , get it off ,
get it off of me . - All right , all right , look .
Just a lighter . - Oh hell , no ,
you ain 't burning me . - JuSt a lighter .
Just a lighter . - Okay .
Okay , okay , okay , okay .
- Shh , Shh . - You burn me , I 'll kill you .
- You all right , you okay ?
- Yeah , I 'm fine .
- Oh . - Huh , what ?
- Hold on .
Put your arms up . - What are you doing ?
Why are you going under my shirt ?
What you doing ? - Jesus .
- Jesus what ?
What , what , what is it ?
What is it , what is it ?
- Anybody got a blowtorch ?
- Stop .
Careful .
- Whoa , whoa !
- If that thing bit you ,
you would be .
Paralyzed like stone for two days .
- What do you call this fella ?
- Laba laba batu , stone spider .
- I may have just discovered a valuable new anesthetic agent
for Wexell-Hall .
- Oh , no , no , no , no .
Forget Wexell , we can get thiS to the highest bidder .
- All right , show and tell 's over .
We gotta got to that boat .
Put your boots on and let 's go .
- Bugger it .
What the hell was that ?
Holy bloody hell .
- Whoa , what was that ?
- Oh , my god .
- What the hell was that ?
- Come on .
- No , no , no , no !
Oh , come on , man !
- What the hell happened ?
- Livingston !
- Here we go .
Ho got drunk and fell off the bloody boat !
- Your friend , your friend !
Now , what we gonna do now ?
Shit !
- Search the wreckage .
Find anything we can use .
And hope to god there 's a phone .
- Oh , come on , come on .
Yes .
- Hello ?
Hello ?
Oh , come on . - Anything ?
- Nothing . - Keep trying .
- What do you think I 'm doing , Jack ?
Hello ?
Shit .
Come on , man , hello ?
- All right , keep looking !
- No phone ?
- Nothing .
- Couldn 't get a signal on the radio .
- Now what ?
- What 's going on ?
- Where 'd these come from ?
- Lopaks . - Who ?
- Local tribe , descended from headhunters .
- What ?
- Been in this region for thousands of years .
- Headhunters ?
- There 's still some villages around here .
- Yeah , it 's supposed to be one of their fishing Spots .
- No , hold on , excuse me .
Did you say headhunters ?
- There haven 't been practicing headhunters in Borneo
for over a century .
- Yeah , well , just because they ain 't practicing
don 't moan they don 't remember how .
- They must be along thiS branch of the river .
If we can find their village , maybe they can lend us a boat .
- So wait a minute ,
we just gonna walk towards the headhunters , not away ?
- Yeah .
- Yeah , yeah , that makes sense .
Oh , god , I 'm so hungry .
I 'd sell my grandmother for a Tic Tac .
- You mention food one more time ,
I 'm voting you off this island .
- Oh , god .
- Is that ?
- Livingston .
- Oh , my god , man .
What the hell happened to him ?
- Anaconda .
- If he was eaten by the snake ,
then why is his body ... - Listen , listen , listen !
All right .
These things are at their weakest when they digest .
But if threatened ,
they will spit up their food and attack again .
- What ?
Are you telling me there 's some Snake out there
with an empty stomach ?
- Yeah .
- The same one that got Ben ?
- No , no .
There 's no way that snake could 've gotten to Livingston .
It had to be another one .
- Another one ?
You said that there wouldn 't be another one tor miles .
- It wouldn 't .
Unless . - Unless what ?
- Unless it 's mating season .
- Oh , my god . - Mating season ?
- Yeah .
You see , the males are territorial ,
but when they smell a female in heat ,
they come running from everywhere .
- Females find a nice , wet , muddy pit ,
and they all go after her at once in one big mating ball .
- So you 're telling me there 's some snake orgy
out in the jungle ? - Yeah , something like that .
Look , we 're losing the light .
All we gotta do is got to that village .
So please , pay attention .
Do not stray from the group .
let 's go .
- Stay quice .
Sacred burial ground .
- Jesus .
- I thought you said that anaconda
was the biggest that you 'd ever seen .
- It was .
- Well , this one 's ... - Bigger .
- The males must 've come through here
looking for the female .
- Some bullshit .
- They took their boats .
- Good for them .
Bad for us .
- Which one 's the Mendranang ?
- On the right .
The Tokut keeps going to the left .
Fastest way to Kotabaru .
- How long ?
- You 'll be soaking in a tub at the Four Seasons
in two days .
- How , man , we don 't even have a boat .
- We 're gonna build one .
- Man , do that in my neighborhood , and that 's your ass .
Shit .
- Sam .
What docs this look like to you ?
- My god .
Perrinia immortalis .
- Now we know why these snakes are so big .
- What ?
- Anacondas keep growing till they die , right ?
And these are the biggest Snakes Bill 's ever Seen .
- Because they 're living longer .
- Exactly .
Because perrinia immortalis is part of the food chain .
These snakes have transcended the Hayflick limit .
The chemical in the orchid does exactly what we predicted .
And not in theory , in the real world .
This is proof , Sam , of your research , carved in stone .
- This is proof ?
It 's anecdotal evidence at best .
- Let 's get to the orchid and find out .
- You are out of your mind .
- Do you have any idea how close we are ?
The orchid was found here on the Mendranang
just around the next bend .
We 'll be going right past it .
- No , we won 't .
We are going down the Tokut .
If we continue down the Mendranang ,
it 's gonna be a week before we reach another village .
I 'm not waiting that long for my bath .
- Yeah , well , it 's not up to you .
- Jack .
Maybe you can just come back .
- Come back ?
In seven years ?
What if it 's not here ?
What if some local farmer decides
to slash and burn the entire basin ?
Instead of the fountain of youth ,
we 'll have a giant rice paddy .
This is our only chance .
You know it is .
Do you really wanna give in when we 're thiS close ?
- Look , you know I got your back , right ?
We 've been in the trenches 100 times together .
But I 'm not going in that jungle .
- Damn straight , man .
- Thank you .
- This is my expedition , and we 're going to the orchid .
- No .
We 're not .
- Don 't be an idiot , Sam .
This is bigger than penicillin , for god 's Sake .
Livce will be saved by this drug .
People will live longer , they 'll stay young longer .
If we don 't put this to human trials ,
it 's gonna be a crime against humanity .
- Two people have died already .
- Scientists have always risked their lives
to change the world .
If they didn 't , we wouldn 't have cures
for yellow fever , polio , and smallpox .
We all knew the risks .
- We thought we did .
Until you decided to Start making decisions
behind our backs .
- What are you talking about ?
- Ho offered Bill an extra 50 grand
to keep going up the Mendranang ,
even though he knew it wasn 't safe .
- Oh , my god .
- Is that tru , Jack ?
- I was thinking of the expedetion .
- You were thinking of your career .
- Look , you 're my assistant .
I don 't need to consult you !
I 'm the one with the authority here .
- We 're in the middle of the jungle , Jack .
At this point , your authority is what we say it is .
- Guess you got a mutiny on your hands .
Thank you .
- Okay , keep it high .
Careful .
Center it right here .
- All right .
- What re you doing ?
- Never seen a man shave before ?
- Probably a lot Sharper before you attacked that alligator .
- Crocodile .
- What 's that mean ?
- That means a new beginning .
It 's Korean .
I got it when I was in the military .
- What brought you here ?
- Long story .
- Where am I gonna go ?
- All right .
Here 's the deal .
I was in the Special Forces ,
and I saw and did things that I wanted to forget .
Sometimes we do the wrong things
for the right reasons , you know ?
- It 's not very long , as stories go .
- Yeah .
Well , I got out of the military ,
came here and bought the Bloody Mary .
Just wanted to start a new life .
- Oh , thank you , Jack .
- On three , ready ?
Ono , two , three . - Two .
- It works . - Whoo !
- All right .
- Let me explain .
- Why in the hell didn 't you tell me about this ?
- The minute someone makes a call , thiS expedition 's over .
- Exactly .
- All I 'm asking for is a few more hours .
We continue on the Mendranang , take our orchid Samples ,
then we call for help .
- Forget about it , Jack , all right ?
I 'm getting us out of here .
- Think about this , Gordon .
You 're about to become a billionaire .
Do you really wanna give all that up ?
- I don 't care about the money , all right ?
I wanna live .
It bit me .
Jack , what are you ?
What re you ?
Help .
- Where 's Mitchell ?
- Resting his feet .
- Should I go get him ? - No , no .
Let him rest till we get everything loaded .
- Okay .
- Those blisters re pretty nasty .
- Mitchell , you okay ?
Mitchell ?
What is it ?
Tell me .
What did you do to him , Jack ?
- What is it ?
- Something is wrong with Mitchell .
- What re you talking about ?
- You were in there alone with him .
What did you do ?
- He was resting his feet .
I didn 't do anything .
- Oh shit . - Oh , my god .
- Oh , my god .
- Gail , no , let 's go ! - No , Mitchell , no !
- Got out , get out , go !
- Come on , come on !
Move , move , move , move , go !
- The raft !
- What ?
No !
You son of a bitch !
- We can build another one .
- With what ?
With what , Sam ?
- We gotta get to the raft .
It 's our only way out of here .
- FYl , Bill , the raft is gone !
- We can get it back .
- How , huh ?
How , we gonna swim after it now ?
- Look , the village is here .
Jack is following the Mendranang .
We cut across the jungle .
We can catch him on the other side .
- Right .
- Catch him where ?
- He 's going to that orchid .
We find that flower ,
we find that raft .
- Oh , thank god .
It 's Jack Byron .
Listen , something terrible has happened .
We took the wrong way on the Mendranang .
We went over a waterfall .
I haven 't seen anyone since .
I think I 'm the only one loft .
- Wait , wait .
Shh , shh , listen .
- Oh , shit . - Come on .
- Okay .
- It 's in front of us .
- Son of a bitch .
It 's trying to separate us .
- What ?
- Oh , shit .
Oh , Christ , it 's everywhere .
- Turn that goddamn thing off .
They can see it . - Doesn 't matter .
They can sense our body heat .
- He 's right .
Let 's just get the hell out of here .
- Which way ?
- Hold on .
- Any way . - Huh ?
- Let 's go , Cole ! - Okay , okay , okay .
Wait , wait for me ! - Come on !
- Hold on , wait for me !
- Oh , my god .
- If there 's a way in , there 's a way out .
- Oh , shit !
Guys ?
- Hey ! - Cole !
- Which way ?
- Over hero ! - Cole !
- All right , say it again , say it again !
- Cole ! - Over here !
Over here , Cole !
- Hello ! - ThiS way , Cole !
- Guys ! - Colo !
- Over here !
- Oh no .
Oh god .
Come on .
Oh , my god !
No , no , no !
No , no . - Cole .
Stay together .
- Okay , I promise .
Now can we please go ?
- Let 's go . - No problem , okay , okay .
Which way ?
- I don 't know . - What ?
What do you mean , you don 't know ?
- I found you , didn 't I ?
- Tran ?
Tran !
Say something !
Oh , shit .
Guys , guys !
- I can see light .
- ls the way out ?
- I don 't know .
- Cole !
Tran !
Can you hear me ?
Colo !
Where are you ?
- I think I found a way out .
- Take this .
Go , now .
- Where re they ?
- Go .
- Oh , my god .
- Help !
- Cole ? - Hey !
- Cole ? - Hey , right here .
- Almost there .
- Holy shit !
Move , it 's coming up my ass !
Help me !
What did I do ?
- Where 's Cole ?
- Cole , Cole ! - Cole , come on !
- Give me your hand .
- Oh , god .
I 'm stuck , I 'm stuck !
I 'm stuck , pull me , man ! - All right , give me your arm .
- Come on !
Oh , my god , it 's coming !
It 's coming !
Pull !
- That 's what I 'm talking about !
That 's what I 'm talking about , Sam !
Oh , my god !
You 're the bomb , Sam !
You Lorena Bobbitt-cd that ass !
How you like her now , bitch , huh ?
She sliced you , she diced you , she cut you up !
That was , like , Sam with the samurai action !
Sam !
- Hell , no .
Colo !
- Colo !
- Cole !
- Got up , Cole .
Oct up , man .
Wake up , man .
Come on , man , wake up .
- No , no , no , no .
- He 's not breathing !
- Give him air , give him air ! - Okay , okay .
- Again , again .
Come on , wake up .
Don 't you die .
Don 't die , come on , no .
- What the fuck ?
Get off me , get off , get off ! - No , no , no .
It 's okay , it 's okay , it 's okay .
- It 's me .
Stay down .
You 're okay . - I 'm okay .
- Yeah . - Yeah .
- You 're okay .
- Perrinia immortalis .
- Son of a bitch finally got his orchid .
- Yeah .
Ho can have them .
All I care about is that raft .
- Let 's go .
Oh , my god , thank god .
- I think I know what happened to Mitchell .
- I can 't let you take that .
You guys look like hell .
- You don 't know what hell is .
- I 'm sorry , but you gave me no choice .
- Did you give Mitchell a choice before you killed him ?
- I didn 't kill Mitchell .
- No , you just let him die .
I saw the spider bite on his arm .
- What was I supposed to do , Sam , huh ?
the right thing ?
- It 's always a good place to start .
- Let 's not be stupid about this .
Let 's get to the flower , we can all go home .
- The mating ball .
- Give me the flare .
Tic him up .
Now !
Fill it up .
- You gotta be kidding me .
- Do I look like I 'm kidding ?
Fill it up !
Oct up !
Now get the flowers . - Okay .
- Throw me the pack .
- Drop the gun !
- Got up , Bill !
Oct up !
Come on , man !
- Got up !
- Sam , come on ! - Sam , come on !
Come on , come on , girl , hurry up !
- Come on ! - Come on !
- Sam , come on ! - Come on , hurry up !
Hurry up , Sam !
Come on , come on !
Come on , baby , come on !
- Shit .
- Come on , baby . - You got it !
- Come on , you 're almost there .
Come on ! - You got it , honey , come on !
- Ah , spider .
- Reach for me !
Come on , Sam , please !
Roach , roach !
- Ah !
- Give me your hand .
- Come on !
- Right here !
- No , no , no !
No !
- Oh , god !
- Come on , Sam , come on !
Keep coming !
Come on , girl .
Climb up that wall , Sam !
Keep moving .
Come on , girl !
Come on , come on , I got you .
Come on , Sam , get back !
- Oh shit , oh shit , oh .
- Hey !
Over here , bitch !
- Holy shit .
Nice shot .
- What can I say ?
I 'm a bad man .
Ah , you two look like you made up .
- He 's not so bad .
- How 's that ?
- Much better .
I think I 'll live .
- Good .
It 's kinda nice having you around .
- So , how much further to my bath ?
- Kotabaru ?
I 'd say another day downriver .
- Whoa , another day ?
Oh , I 'm not rowing another day , homeboy .
- All right .
Let 's see , we got this Shortcut , right up ...
- No !
â  ª You ask for questions when you already know why â  ª
â  ª Looking for empathy when you can 't cry â  ª
â  ª You give it away â  ª
â  ª You give it all away â  ª
â  ª You 're giving it all away for one more try â  ª
â  ª We have reached the mountains â  ª
â  ª As they crumble down into the sea â  ª
â  ª Fire falling from the sky â  ª
â  ª Joy in our security â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª It 's malovolent â  ª
â  ª All fear is born inside â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª Seems it 's never meant â  ª
â  ª For anyone else but you â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª It 's malovolent â  ª
â  ª All fear is born inside â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª Seems it 's never meant â  ª
â  ª For anyone else but you â  ª
â  ª You 've made mistakes â  ª
â  ª And you wish them all away â  ª
â  ª What was up is coming down , you Stumble â  ª
â  ª You give it a kiss â  ª
â  ª You kiss it all away â  ª
â  ª You 're kissing it all away for one last try â  ª
â  ª We have reached the fountains â  ª
â  ª That were all flowing endlessly â  ª
â  ª Hunger growing in our gut â  ª
â  ª Awakens us in unity â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª It 's malovolent â  ª
â  ª All fear is born inside â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª Seems it 's never meant â  ª
â  ª For anyone else but you â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª It 's malovolent â  ª
â  ª All fear is born inside â  ª
â  ª Chapow â  ª
â  ª Seems it 's never meant â  ª
â  ª For anyone else but you â  ª
â  ª Ah ah ah â  ª